Mom.
妈
What have you been up to lately?
你最近忙什么呢
You should go home sometime.
你有空回家看看呀
Mom.
妈
I'm on a business trip,
我出差呢 在路上
going to the airport.
去机场
Business trip?
出差啊
No big deal, it's just that
没事 就是那个
your dad's older brother,
你爸的大哥
Xin's uncle,
心心的大伯
is coming tomorrow.
他明天过来
Can you make it
那你明天
back for dinner tomorrow?
能不能赶回来吃饭哪
Mom, I can't make it back.
妈 我回不去啦
When is my uncle arriving?
我大伯什么时候到啊
I'll have the driver pick him up
我让司机接一下吧
and follow him.
然后有事跟着他
Okay.
好好好
Haowen,
浩文
When you're back from your trip,
那个 你出差回来
check on Xin.
你看看心心
Got it, Mom.
我知道了 妈
I'll hang up now.
那我挂啦
Mr Jia, where are we going now?
贾总 我们现在去哪里
Back to the office.
回公司吧
My mother-in-law has a visitor tomorrow.
岳母家明天来人
Go pick him up
你去接一下啊
and follow him.
然后就跟着他
I won't go.
我就不去了
Tell them I'm on a business trip.
说我出差了
Okay.
好的
Understood, Mr Jia.
我知道了 贾总
Is this enough?
这下够了吧
Two more.
再加俩
No amount of this
摆多少
will ease the anxiety inside.
也缓解不了内心的紧张
Anxiety?
紧张
Of course.
那可不
Why anxious?
怎么紧张了呢
Since Mom left,
打从妈走了
he's been sitting here,
就一直坐在这儿
not moving.
没动过地儿
Isn't it anxiety?
不是紧张 是啥呀
I get it.
我懂
It's that fear of
不就是即将
being controlled
被老大支配的
by the elder, right?
那种恐惧感吗
It's okay, Dad.
没事啊 爸
We're the same.
咱俩一样
This time is different.
这次不一样
How is it different?
怎么不一样啊
He lied.
撒谎啦
It's worse.
性质恶劣
Who knows how uncle
一会儿大爷来
will react when he arrives.
指不定怎么咆哮呢
What should we do?
这可怎么办才好呢
Dad.
爸
That's your fault.
这就是你的不对了
He's here.
来了
You should have at least
你怎么也得打电话
called me.
告诉我一声
You...
你这
- Guangrong. - You should've told me.
大哥 这要说呀得
You brought so much stuff.
你拿那么些东西
Guanghua,
我的弟弟呀
you...
你说你
you made me so worried.
你可把我急死了你啊
I'm fine.
好了
Well.
这
What's Dad doing?
爸干吗呢
Showing off to uncle
要给大爷展示一下
that he's doing well.
他挺好
Making moves.
扭两下
Good, good.
好好好 好
Better than I expected.
比我想得好
Sit.
快坐
Uncle.
大爷
Have a seat.
你快坐
Sit down.
快坐 快坐啊
You sit.
你坐 你坐
They told me on the way that
路上他们跟我说啊
you're recovering well.
你恢复得不错
I didn't believe it.
我根本不相信
In yesterday's video call,
你看看昨天打电话
I saw your mouth was crooked.
我看你这个嘴啊 歪
I thought...
那我一想啊 这
I was so worried.
你看可把我急得呀
I barely slept last night.
我这一宿没怎么睡都
He's recovering well.
恢复不错
But no matter what,
但是不管怎么样
you should have
这个事出了
told me about it.
你得告诉我啊
He didn't want us to call you.
他不让给你打电话呀
Yes.
对
Why didn't you
你怎么不让
want them to call me?
他们给我打电话呢
He doesn't exercise.
他还不锻炼
Sometimes.
有时候
He doesn't eat properly.
他还不好好吃饭
That's your fault.
这就是你的不对了
Well,
不是
he didn't want to tell me,
他不让告诉我
he didn't eat and exercise.
他不吃饭 不锻炼
What about you?
你们干啥的
No.
不是
He didn't listen.
说了不听嘛 不让说
We've been waiting for you.
这不盼着你来呢吗
You should criticize him.
你赶快好好批评批评他
Guanghua,
老弟啊
you didn't want them to tell me.
你说你不让告诉我
Do you know
你知不知道
your recovery
你恢复得好与坏
and your body
你的身体
concerns the whole family?
揪着全家人的心哪
You can't just think about yourself.
你不能考虑自己啊
You can't ignore me.
你不能不考虑我
Well...
那个
You go ahead.
你说
What's wrong?
怎么了
Nothing.
没事
What were you going to say?
你想说啥
Anything else you're hiding from me?
还有啥事瞒着我
Well...
不 不
I was afraid you'd
怕你着急
get upset.
上火
That's all?
你憋了半天就
You shouldn't keep it from me
你不能 不不 怕我着急
just because of that.
就不告诉我
That's wrong.
这是不对的
Quite flexible.
挺灵活啊
Come on.
来来来 你你你
Try clapping again. Let me see.
你再拍拍 我 我看看
Clap with both hands.
两手拍
Clap harder.
你拍拍拍 使点劲
Come on, let me see.
来来 我看看
Clap, clap.
拍 拍
Let me check.
我检查检查你
Come on.
来来来
Keep going.
来 接着来
Both hands.
两手
You even have rhythm.
还打 打上拍子了都
Okay.
行 行行行
Now I feel relieved.
这我心里踏实了
I've been worried.
我 我这心一直揪着
You know?
你知道吗
Have some water.
喝点水 喝点水
Now I'm relieved.
这我心里踏实了
It's okay.
没事 没事
He can do it.
行 行 他行
He's recovering well.
确实恢复得不错
You're right.
你说对了
It's really impressive.
真的 很难得呀
He's had a good foundation
他底子好
since he was young.
他打小底子就好
He's even serving me water.
这还给我倒水呢
Come on, hand it over.
来来来 你递给我
Hand it over.
递给我
Drink.
喝
Good.
行啊
Isn't it great?
是不是挺好啊
He practiced all morning.
练一上午了
Practicing serving water?
就练倒水啊
Fine,
来
serve me another one.
你再给我倒一杯
Come on.
来来来
Another one.
倒一杯
Do it.
倒
Do it well.
倒一杯
Do it again, Dad.
再倒一杯 爸
He's even teasing me.
还逗上了
Alright, alright.
好好好 好好好
Look at them.
你说他们哥儿俩
Guanghua,
老弟呀
I brought
我给你
your favorite pickles.
带了你最爱吃的酸菜
Wait and see,
你看看 你等着
I'll make you pickled fish.
我给你做个酸菜鱼
Not today.
今天不做了
Let's go out to eat.
咱们出去吃
Go out.
出去吃
Why go out?
出去吃干啥
I've booked the place.
地儿都订好了
I've had it arranged.
我都安排好了
Really?
是吗
Do as she says.
听大姑娘的
Okay.
好好好 好好好
Distinguished guests,
好 尊贵的各位来宾
today we're having
今天我们吃的
a "Double 16 Feast."
叫做十六回切
Before we start, we have
开始之前 它有
four nuts, four fruits,
四干果 四水果
four pastries, and four cold dishes.
四糕点 四冷碟
After serving the dishes, we'll have
上菜之后
four main courses, four mixed dishes,
它有四大菜 四拌菜
four vegetables, and four desserts.
四时蔬 四点心
That's a total of 32 dishes.
总共三十二道菜
32 dishes?
三十二道菜
We won't finish that.
吃不完哪 你这这
Isn't that a bit of a waste?
你这多少有点浪费啊
The plates are small.
盘小
Uncle, let me tell you,
大伯 我跟你讲啊
this "Double 16 Feast"
听说这十六回切呀
is an
它是一个
intangible cultural heritage.
非物质文化遗产
What we're experiencing today
我们今天吃的
isn't just food,
不是东西
it's cultural
是感受文化
heritage, right?
传承 是吧
They say
人家说了
it's the highest standard feast
这是宴请亲朋好友
for hosting family
最高规格的
and friends.
家宴
Actually, we've never had it before.
其实我们也没吃过
Since you're here,
这不是您来了吗
we're honored to try it
沾您光 我们也尝尝
and experience it.
感受一下
Am I...
这这这 这
Am I that important?
我有那么重要吗
Absolutely.
必须的
Definitely.
必须
But you know what I love to eat.
但是我爱吃啥 你知道
I can't live without pickles.
我顿顿离不开榨菜
This...
这
No, no, I'm fine.
不不 我没事没事没事
I'm fine.
我随便啊
I can eat anything.
我什么都能吃
I've tasted all kinds of
我这么多年
hardships over the years.
我什么苦都尝过
No need to say.
别说
This is definitely a treat.
这当然是享福了
Definitely.
这是啊
Yes.
对
At this age,
到这岁数了
you should enjoy.
得享福了
Yes.
是 是 是
It's my first time.
我这还头一回呢
I noticed I didn't recognize
我刚刚看那个桌上
many of the dishes on the table.
好像都 我 我不认识
There are fruits and pastries.
有水果 点心
But I don't recognize the rest.
但是 其他的我不认识
I'll show you.
我带你过去看看去
Go.
看看
This place is great.
这地儿真好
So many dishes. Is it too much?
这么多菜 点太多了吧
No.
不多
It's rare for uncle to come.
那大爷难得来一次
We have to treat him well
可不得给他招待好了
and show my dad's generosity.
得给我爸撑撑面嘛
How much will this cost?
你这面子得花多少钱哪
Alright, I'll pick some.
行了 我挑一挑啊
You go up and chat with them.
你上去陪他们聊天吧
Okay?
好吧
Haowen used to
那以前这事
handle these things.
都是浩文张罗
Can you manage?
你行吗
Of course I can.
我怎么不行啊
Don't look down on me.
你瞧不起谁呢
He only managed
那以前他张罗
because I asked him to.
都是我让他张罗的
I can handle this.
这点事我还弄不明白吗
You're so capable.
你看把你能的
Is he coming or not?
一会儿他来不来
I don't know.
不知道啊
He's probably busy.
估计忙着呢吧
Give him a call.
你给他打一电话
You call him.
你给他打
You should call.
你打
You let him arrange the car.
这车都是你让他安排的
Call him.
你接着打
I'll check this.
我 我看看这个
Hurry.
快快快
Okay, I'll call.
行 我打 我打
What did he say? Is he coming?
怎么说啊 来吗
No one answers.
没人接
He's probably in a meeting.
估计开会呢吧
Try again later.
一会儿你再打
How about adding some abalone?
再加个鲍鱼怎么样
Up to you.
都听你的
Why is no one answering?
怎么还没人接呀
Try again later. He's in a meeting.
一会儿再打 他开会呢
If you
你这
call too often,
频繁地打
he won't be able to answer.
他哪儿能接呀
Later.
你一会儿
Call again later.
一会儿 一会儿
Okay.
行
Do you want to add anything else?
你看看还想吃点什么
That's enough.
够啦
Goodness.
天哪
You've set a whole table of food.
你这整一大桌子菜
In the past,
这 这要搁过去啊
this is something
这得是大户人家
only a big family can afford.
才能吃得起的
Guangrong,
大哥
we're a big family too.
我们也是大户人家
We have three generations.
你看我们都三代同堂了
Isn't that a big family?
那还不是大户啊
Yes.
是是
Let me tell you,
我跟你说 这些
these are local
可是我们当地的
specialties.
特色菜啊
After eating this,
你吃完这些
you won't need to try anywhere else.
其他地方你不用去吃了
So, are you saying
那你的意思是
I can only eat this one meal?
我吃了这顿没下顿呗
No,
不 不
I understand what you mean.
我理解弟妹的意思
Guanghua,
老弟啊
you're really blessed.
你可真是个有福之人哪
This family is so
这一家人坐在一起
harmonious.
其乐融融
And I've found that
另外我发现
Chunjiang is really
春江这个地方
a great place.
真是个风水宝地
It's nurturing.
养人哪
Right?
你看看
Remember when you
当年你送我们
sent us off?
离开的时候
You were reluctant.
你那舍不得啊
You still remember that.
这事你还记得
Really petty of you.
真是小心眼啊
Indeed!
真是
We're brothers,
你说我们老哥儿俩
when one left,
走一个
wouldn't the other feel lonely?
我一个人不觉得孤单吗
Now it's good.
现在好了
Both of your daughters
你们家这俩姑娘
are having
你看看
their second child.
都生二胎了
Isn't it?
是不是
Look.
你看
Kid,
孩子
what should you call me?
你管我叫啥
Grandpa.
大姥爷呀
See, she knows.
你看看她就知道
Now, with just
现在你说有一家
one child per family,
一家就一个孩子
the child has no aunts,
没有姑姑
uncles, or cousins,
叔叔啊 姨啥的
won't it be lonely in the future?
你说将来多孤单哪
Yes.
对
Uncle,
大爷
if you like it here,
您要是喜欢这儿啊
you can stay and
您就在这儿待着
keep my dad company.
陪着我爸
Stay as long as you want.
想待多久待多久
That's right.
没错
Grandpas and grandma,
大姥爷 姥爷 姥姥
you all live well.
你们都好好的
I'll work hard to
我努力啊
achieve four generations.
四世同堂
See?
你看看
I like children
我就喜欢这样
with such ambition.
有志气的孩子
Kid,
孩子
tell me how many
你告诉大姥爷
children you're having in the future.
将来你准备要几个孩子
Well...
不
Yunjie is only 15 and hasn't
云阶今年才十五岁呢
even finished middle school.
初中还没毕业呢
Yeah, you...
对 你这
I asked too early.
我我 问早了我
Just kidding.
开玩笑 开玩笑
Grandpa will take it seriously.
大姥爷会当真的
Yes.
就是
Just joking.
开玩笑
Nonsense.
瞎说
Come on, let's start eating.
来 咱们动筷吧
Wait.
别别别
Where is
那谁
the second son-in-law?
我怎么没看着二姑爷呢
Where is he?
人呢
He's busy with work.
他那个工作忙
No need to wait for him.
不用等他
Dad,
爸
propose a toast.
您提一杯
Let's start.
我们先开始吧
Let's start first.
咱们先开始吧 先开始
Alright.
好 好 来
Wait.
别别别
Guanghua,
老弟啊
this is no rush.
咱不差这一会儿
Our family shouldn't
咱一家人呢
be missing anyone.
一个都不能缺
We'll wait.
咱们等
Wait.
等
Okay.
好 好 好
Coming.
来了 来了
I'm here.
我来了
Uncle.
大爷
Uncle,
大爷 大爷
I'm so sorry, really sorry.
真对不起 对不起
The whole family is here,
全家欢迎您来春江
yet I'm late.
我这还迟到
I'm really sorry.
太不像话了
Dad, Mom,
爸 妈
I got caught up with something.
我刚耽误了点事啊
How about this?
这样
I'll have three shots first.
我 我先自罚三杯啊
Here.
来 来
I'll take the liquor.
黄的 我拿白的吧
I'll drink a whole pot.
我干一壶
Uncle,
大爷
this is the good wine my dad saved.
我爸存的好酒
Isn't it enough?
我喝少啦
We haven't started eating yet.
我们还没开席呢
Come on.
来来来 来
Everyone, raise your glasses.
来 大家都把杯举起来
Raise your glasses.
来 来 都把杯举起来
Come on.
来
Welcome my brother,
欢迎我哥哥
your uncle, to Chunjiang.
你们大爷 来春江
Cheers.
来
Welcome, uncle.
欢迎大爷 欢迎大爷
Thanks.
添麻烦了啊
How's it?
怎么样
Do you like it?
喝得惯吗
I'm okay.
我还行
This is
这 这是那个
green tea, right?
那那 绿茶 是吧
Yes.
对 对
We used to drink floral tea.
咱东北都愿意喝花茶
You know, right?
是不是 你知道
But now,
但现在 也变了
many people drink green tea.
也不少人都喝绿茶
But I won't drink it.
但是我 我是不会喝
Time
想想这时间
really flies.
过得可真快啊
Tomorrow,
一想
I'll be
我明天
going back.
就要回去了
Strange, isn't it?
人怪 你说啊
When you two left back then,
当年你们俩走的时候吧
I felt bad too,
心里也难受
but it's a
但是 那种难受
different feeling
和明天我要走
than I having to leave
两个滋味
tomorrow.
不一样
Guangrong.
哥
Maybe it's because I'm older
也许年龄大了
and more sentimental.
容易伤感
Guanghua.
老弟啊
Guangrong.
哥
I need to go back.
走啊 得回去
They need me.
家里也需要我
I can't be away.
离开我也不行
My grandson
那小孙子
has been acting up.
这两天闹的啊
My son keeps
那儿子天天
sending me voice messages,
给我发的那语 语音
not directly urging me to go back,
嘴上不说催我回去
but saying, "Dad,
还总说 爸呀
spend more time with my uncle."
你在这儿多陪陪我老叔
But he actually
其实心里啊
wants me to come back sooner.
还是让我早点回去
I know.
我知道
I didn't sleep well last night,
我昨晚没睡好
thinking a lot.
想了很多很多
But today,
但是今天
I don't know what to say.
也不知道想说啥
I just
就是啊
want to remind you two
我想嘱咐你们二位啊
that even though we're
虽然我们已经到了
at the age to enjoy life,
享受生活的年龄了
Guanghua,
老弟啊
you need to know
你得知道啊
how to protect yourself.
善于保护自己啊
Look at
你看看
all kinds of
社会上这些 这
chaos in society.
这些乱七八糟事太多了
So
所以
don't answer
就不熟悉的电话
unknown calls.
一定不能接啊
Everything is under
因为现在
real-name registration now.
什么都实名制了
We're in the open,
我们在明处
but scammers are in the dark.
那些小骗子都在暗处
It's easy to get tricked.
弄不好就上当受骗
I'm speaking the truth.
我说的都是实话
Yes.
是
So,
所以说呢
if you're sick,
有病
trust doctors and science.
相信医生 相信科学
All in all,
说一千道一万
self-care
还离不开自身
is necessary.
对自身的要求
Exercise regularly.
加强锻炼
You must exercise.
一定要锻炼
I see you have an
我看着你那儿有一个
appliance
蹬的那个
for pedaling.
那个 那个设备
Don't just use that thing at home.
你别老在家蹬那玩意儿
Listen,
我告诉你
walking is
干蹬不走道
the way better than that.
有什么意思啊
Just walk.
你走
Walk everyday.
每天你就走
Listen,
我告诉你啊
8,000 to 10,000 steps are best.
八千到一万步最好
I suggest you walk
我建议 逛大街
and explore the city.
走街串巷
Even if you've lived here
你别看你在这个城市
for decades,
生活了几十年
there are streets and alleys
有些街道 有些胡同
you haven't explored.
你根本就没走过
Right?
是不是
Yes.
是是是
Look,
你看看
if you pay attention,
如果你心细一点啊
you'll notice
你就会发现
subtle changes
这个城市每一天
in the city
都会有不同的
every day.
微妙的变化
You'll end up
你不知不觉
walking 10,000 steps
这一万多步出去了
without feeling tired.
还不觉得累
Come back, wash up,
回来洗洗
eat if you're hungry,
饿了吃点东西
and take a nap.
睡一觉
Isn't that
多好啊
nice?
是不是啊
Yeah.
当然
But
还是
be careful
你就得注意
not to get lost.
容易走丢
Have your kids
你让孩子啊
buy a GPS watch for you.
买一块那个能定位的表
That way,
这样呢
you can walk freely,
自己走着呢 踏实
and they won't worry.
孩子也放心
Am I being a bit wordy?
我是不是有点啰嗦了
No.
不 不
Not at all.
不啰嗦
I...
大哥
But let me tell you,
但是 我告诉你啊
this is just a suggestion.
我这只是建议
Well, Ningli,
弟妹啊 就是
as long as
在不影响和干扰
it doesn't
你们家
disrupt your life,
正常生活的情况下
you can consider it.
你适当地考虑考虑
Sure.
会 会 会
Yeah.
对
I don't know
也 也 也不
what else to say.
不知道说啥了
Guangrong,
哥
I remember it all.
我都记住了
Guanghua,
老弟啊
how many more times
咱这辈子
will we see each other?
还能见几面啊
Guangrong.
大哥
we'll come back to visit you.
我们会回去看你的
I suggest
我建议
you go back when you
你们还没事真是
have time.
回去看看
We
回去
Definitely.
一定回
Guangrong,
哥
I've got a gift for you.
我给你准备了一件礼物
Let me show you.
我带你去看看去
No, I won't take it.
不是 我啥也不拿
Let's go.
走走走 走
No,
不不不
I don't need anything.
我 我啥也不需要
- I don't need. - Come have a look.
家都有 来看看
Let's go.
走走 听话
No.
不不不
Have a look.
你看看
I don't need it.
我不要啊
Come.
来来来 是
Mr Zhou,
周总
here's last week's industry report
这是上周出差的
from the business trip.
行业报告
Take a look.
您看一下
Thank you.
辛苦了
It's my job.
应该的
How about checking out
要不要去山里的
a high-end guesthouse
高档民宿
in the mountains?
体验一下
Consider it a hotel industry review
就当考察下酒店行业
and a break for yourself.
也给自己放个假
That sounds good,
这是好事啊
but...
可是
Let Mr Yu take care of the child.
让于总照顾孩子嘛
Hasn't he been active lately?
他最近不是积极表现吗
Offer him a chance.
让他好好表现
Let's go for a walk in the mountains.
我们去 山里走走
I'd rather not.
还是算了吧
I just got back from a trip.
这不刚出差回来吗
Besides,
而且
I don't want to give him false hope.
不要给他无谓的幻想
It's fine.
没关系
Mr Yu's in a good mood lately.
于总最近心情好啊
Look,
你看
he sent me the report.
他给我抄送的报告啊
Xinmiao's under scrutiny.
新苗被监管
Blue Ocean is set to win.
蓝海要躺赢了
What does that mean?
什么意思啊
Look,
你看
Xinmiao was penalized for
新苗因为算法违规
algorithm violations.
被处罚了
The editor-in-chief was suspended.
主编被停职
Blue Ocean is back
蓝海重新回到
in the top spot.
第一的位置
Yu Hai called me
于海呢 给我打电话
to have a meeting to discuss
说要开会讨论一下
next steps.
下一步怎么办
He wants to take down Xinmiao completely.
要彻底把新苗打趴
Editor-in-chief suspended indefinitely?
主编无限期停职
Mr Zhou, I'm sorry.
周总 对不起啊
Then give me these two tickets.
那 这两张票都给我吧
I'll check it out for you.
我替你去体验体验
No, you...
不 你
Who are you going with?
你要跟谁去啊
Xinmiao's editor-in-chief,
新苗主编
Xu Meng'an.
许梦安
Why are you
好好的带我出来
taking me out?
兜什么风啊
Are you two so free?
你们两个这么闲呀
Don't you need to work?
不用上班啊
I am working.
我在上班啊
The resort we're visiting today
今天要去的度假村呢
is a project our company
就是我们公司
is evaluating.
要考察的项目
Fine,
行
what you're doing is jobbery.
你是假公济私
What about you?
我姐 你呢
I wasn't feeling well yesterday,
我昨天不太舒服
so I asked for a leave.
所以今天请假
I'll rest for two days.
我休息两天
What's wrong?
你哪儿不舒服啊
Nothing, just a normal reaction.
没事 就正常反应
You should rest
那你也应该在家
at home then.
好好歇着呀
Have your husband stay with you.
让姐夫陪着你嘛
He can't.
他陪不了
He said he's busy today.
他说他今天有点忙
Busy with what?
他有什么可忙的
I won't divorce.
我不离婚
What if he cheats?
他要是出轨了呢
What about a serious illness?
重大疾病呢
I won't divorce.
不弃
That's good.
挺好
But also quite annoying.
也挺糟心
Who brought up
那离婚这事
divorce first?
是谁先提出来的
This time it was Haowen.
这次是浩文
This time?
这一次
Any other times?
那还有哪一次啊
Previously,
就 之前
when Dad was ill,
我把爸气生病那一次
but that was
但那次我就是
just mentioning,
说说而已啊
I didn't mean it.
我没有当真
Haowen is serious this time.
浩文这次 他是认真的
To be honest,
我说实话啊
up to now,
到现在为止
I don't think Haowen
我也不觉得浩文
wants to divorce you.
愿意跟你离婚
Yeah,
是啊
I don't think he's the type
我也觉得他不是那种
to abandon his family.
抛妻弃子的人啊
I don't know Haowen well,
我对浩文不是很了解啊
but if he brought up divorce,
但是他要提出离婚
there must be a reason.
那一定是有原因的
Maybe I'm just too act up.
那就是我太作了
But since I got pregnant,
可是自从怀二胎之后
I've been sick.
我就生病了
I'm already seeing a doctor.
我现在已经在看病了
So, you see,
那你看
I'm not having any extreme thoughts
我没有那些过激的
anymore,
想法了
right?
对不对
No.
不是
That's what the doctor said.
人家大夫是这么说的啊
Pregnant women will be more or less
这个产妇在前期和后期
depressed before and after birth,
多少都会有点抑郁
varying in severity.
只是程度不同罢了
So
所以呢
don't just equate
你也不要把自己
yourself with a patient.
直接跟病人就划等号
Okay?
好吧
Mengxin,
梦心啊
have you made up your mind?
你是不是想好了
That no matter what he does,
不管他做什么
you won't divorce?
你都不会离婚
Yes, I won't divorce.
不离婚
Haowen treats me very well.
浩文对我很好
I know it.
我知道
Then just hang on.
那就拖着
Yes, hang on.
对 拖着
This isn't the time
现在也不是
to make decisions.
做决定的时候
Maybe over time,
也许时间久了
you'll understand why.
就知道他为什么了
Is that what you do?
你也是用的这招吗
How long did it take?
花了多长时间
Yu Hai,
于海
you need to handle this.
这事你得管哪
Right now,
你现在马上
call immediately
立刻 打电话
and get Huang Sisi
把那黄思思
removed from Xinmiao.
从新苗给我弄走
I mean, senior,
不是 我说师哥
you never
你这八百辈子
contacted me before.
不找我一回
Now you need me
找我你就让我
to handle this?
给你干这个
Listen,
我跟你说啊
Huang Sisi
这黄思思
used to be at Blue Ocean,
以前是在我们蓝海
but now she's at Xinmiao.
但是她现在去新苗了
Can I manage that?
我 这事我能管得着吗
What's her relationship with you?
黄思思跟你什么关系
You don't know?
你不知道啊
No, what relationship?
不是 跟我什么关系
We're just
我们俩就是
superior and subordinate.
上下级的关系
We have
我们俩其他
nothing else.
没有半毛钱关系啊
I've
这话
made it clear
我跟你们家梦安
to Meng'an
还有我们家婉真
and Wanzhen.
我都说得很清楚了
I'll say it again,
我现在再说一遍
we have no relationship.
我们俩没有任何关系
You should know
那黄思思
what kind of person
是一个怎么样的人
Huang Sisi is.
你应该很清楚吧
Her tactics
她的那些手段
and tricks,
那些伎俩
didn't she learn from you?
不是跟你学的吗
Well,
那
honestly,
我说句难听的话啊
I suspect
我很怀疑这件事情
you're behind this.
背后的主使他就是你
Where does that come from?
这都哪儿跟哪儿啊
What do you mean?
什么哪儿跟哪儿啊
Am I wrong?
我说得不对吗
Where are you going?
你干什么
I'm talking to you.
我跟你说话呢
I'm going to pee.
我上厕所
Go ahead.
那你上呗
Why close the door?
关什么门啊
I need to pee.
我上厕所
Is there a problem?
我不关门 我
Why are you afraid?
你上个厕所 你怕什么
Just pee. I'll talk.
你尿你的 我说我的
You stand there watching.
你站那儿看着我
I can't pee.
我尿不出来
Just pee. I'll talk.
你先尿的 我说着
I don't care
我不管你
about your relationship
和那个黄思思
with Huang Sisi.
是什么关系
What relationship?
我什么关系呀 我
Shout if you want. I don't care.
你喊 我不管了
Anyway,
总而言之
if you're going to
你们要搞事情
cause trouble,
你们出去搞
do it elsewhere.
到别处去搞
Your actions are making Meng'an
你现在搞得我们家梦安
suffer.
她受委屈了
Meng'an is feeling
我们家梦安现在
wronged.
很冤枉
Are you going to pee or not?
你尿不尿到底
I can't pee, senior.
我尿不出来 师哥
I really can't.
我尿 我真尿不出来
I quit.
我不尿了
Senior, senior.
师哥 师哥
You still remember
你张口一个师哥
I'm your senior?
闭口一个师哥
"Great virtue promotes growth."
厚德载物
"Knowledge and action are one."
知行合一
You've betrayed
这个校训
our school motto.
已经被你践踏了
What's this about?
什么呀 这这
What are you doing?
你在搞什么
You've ruined Xinmiao.
你把新苗搞垮了
Is this what you wanted?
你是不是如愿以偿了
You're not just
你不是在
ruining a company.
搞垮一个公司啊
You're destroying a family.
你是在粉碎一个家庭
How am I destroying
我什么就粉碎
your family?
你们一个家庭了
Talking that to someone
你当着我这么一个
who has a broken family?
家庭粉碎了的人说这话
What do you mean?
有意思吗
Always talking about Meng'an,
一口一个你们家梦安
Meng'an.
你们家梦安
Showing off in front of me,
当着我个单身狗
a single man.
撒狗粮呢
Are you?
跟我这儿凡尔赛呢
Let me tell you,
我跟你说
my old fellow.
我老班长
Meng'an
就你们家梦安
is not someone
那是个吃亏的人
easy to mess with.
省油的灯吗
If she fights with
她 如果跟黄思思
Huang Sisi,
她们俩斗起来
who knows who will win?
不一定谁能斗过谁呢
Right?
对吧
You...
你
And
再说啊
if it really gets bad,
实在不行了
I'll cover for her,
我给她兜着
okay?
好不好
She can come to Blue Ocean
她到我蓝海来
and be a director.
她跟我这儿当总监
How about that?
你看这样 总可以了吧
You cover for her?
你兜着
She's pregnant now.
她现在是孕妇
Can you handle it
出什么事
if something happens?
你兜得住吗
Well,
不是
so what should I do?
那我怎么办哪 我这
I don't care.
今天我不管
Meng'an has suffered
反正我们家梦安
anyway.
她吃亏了
You need to find
你得想个办法
a solution.
给我解决了
I don't have any.
我没办法
You...
你
I have a solution for you.
我给你个办法
Call Huang Sisi now,
你现在打电话
tell her
你告诉黄思思
to apologize in front of the whole
当着全公司的人的面
company
道歉
and take full
承担这件事情
responsibility for this.
所有的后果和责任
Make the call. That's it.
打电话吧 就这样
You're killing me.
逼死我你是要
What are you doing?
你干什么
Don't be impulsive.
别冲动啊
I...
我
I need to breathe.
我透口气 我
I can't get out.
我我
Yu Hai,
于海
think about it,
你好好想想
Meng'an is pregnant.
梦安可是个孕妇啊
It's not mine.
不是 那又不是我的
Hey.
去
Look up.
你看看上边
God is watching
人在做
your every move.
天在看
Goodness.
我去
God is fair.
老天爷还是公平的
So don't worry about
所以不要
momentary gains and losses.
计较一时的得失
Even if I failed in marriage,
你看我虽然婚姻失败了
my career is
但是我现在的事业
successful now.
很成功啊
I feel like I've lived up
我觉得我活出了
to my worth.
自己的价值
Are you
那
really
他出轨
okay with his cheating?
你真的不介意吗
Of course,
介意啊
I'm not okay with it.
当然介意
Lin,
姐夫
why are you here?
你怎么来啦
I'm looking for Mr Zhang.
我找你们张总
Is he here?
在吗
He is.
他在
You're here
你是为了
for that thing, right?
那天的事来的吧
Follow me.
走 我带你去
Thanks.
谢谢
Lin,
姐夫
Listen,
这事啊 我跟你说啊
you need to have a serious
你可得找张总
talk with Mr Zhang.
好好说道说道
Meng'an has been wronged.
梦安可是受了大委屈了
Mr Zhang,
张总
Meng'an's husband,
梦安的爱人
Li Lin, is here to see you.
李临来找您了
Li Lin,
李临
it's been years.
好几年不见了
I hardly recognize you.
我都快认不出来了
Mr Zhang.
张总
Where's Meng'an?
梦安呢
She's not well and resting at home.
她不舒服 在家躺着呢
Well,
你看这
look,
你说这
I was planning to visit her today.
今天我还想去看看她呢
What a coincidence.
也 也巧了
Please have a seat.
你快坐着歇会儿
No.
不坐了
I'll be brief.
我长话短说
Go ahead.
您 您说
Mr Zhang,
张总
Meng'an has been
我们家梦安
with you
跟随着你
from the magazine to Xinmiao,
从杂志社到新苗
going through
风风雨雨
all the ups and downs,
坎坎坷坷
working hard
鞍前马后
with no complains, right?
任劳任怨 是不是
Yes.
是是是
She's taken on more than others
做得比别人多
while getting less.
拿得比别人少
Less?
少吗
Not really.
是不少
She's had
您给她画的饼
plenty of empty promises.
我们家梦安可吃得不少
No,
不是
the company's in a tough spot now,
现在这公司状况不太好
but when things improve,
等公司缓过来啊
I'll make it up to her.
我再给她补回去
No, don't bother.
不不不 不用了
No more promises.
不用再画饼了
We don't care about money.
拿多拿少我们不计较
As long as Meng'an
只要我们家梦安
feels she's with
觉得是跟对了人
the right boss,
跟对了老板
we can accept that.
我们也就认了
But you can't make her
但是你不能让她
feel
在
wronged
在这个公司
in this company.
里面受委屈啊
Yes, yes, I understand.
是 是 是这样
I wanted
本来呢
to find someone
我觉着她怀孕了
to help
我想找个人
since she's pregnant,
给她分担一下
but I didn't expect
这没想到
things have gotten this bad.
事情发展到这个地步
You need to find the right person.
那你找人得找对人呢
Don't you know
黄思思
what kind of person
是一个什么来路
Huang Sisi is?
你不知道吗
You put her in the company
你把她安排到公司里来
to sabotage Meng'an
整天给她使绊子
and then make her
出了问题之后
take the blame.
让她背黑锅
She's one of your veterans.
她可是你的元老啊
Think about it.
你想一想 是不是
You treat her like that.
你就这么对她
She'll be disheartened.
她的心会寒的
In that case,
那这样的话
what's the point of
她在这个公司里 待着
her staying here?
还 还有什么意义呢
Is it?
是不是
Li Lin, calm down.
李临 消消气啊
It's just a fight.
不就是打个人吗
It's fine.
打就打了
I want to fire her anyway.
反正我也不想再用她了
What do you mean?
打就打了是什么意思
You're going to fight
你还要对我们家
with Meng'an?
梦安动手
You wanna fire her?
还要开除她吗
What's going on? This company
怎么回事 这个公司
allows violence now?
还纵容打孕妇了吗
Who?
谁啊
No, no, no.
没没没
It's not about violence.
打什么孕妇啊
Well,
这 这
your wife grabbed her by the hair
你 你老婆揪着头发
and beat her up.
把人家给揍了
You see, she's pregnant.
你说她还怀着孕呢
She must be really fierce.
她得有多猛
Look, she hit someone
你看 她打完人
and I have to go
我还得拎着东西
visit her.
去看她
What?
什么
Rachel.
瑞秋
Get out.
滚
Is Meng'an really okay?
梦安真没事吧
She's fine.
没事
Your sister
你姐
at least got some revenge for me.
也算是替我出了口气
She beat her up.
把她给打了
When did this happen?
什么时候的事
It's over now.
过去了
Why didn't you let me help you?
你怎么不让我帮你呢
You're pregnant,
你这大着肚子呢
what if something went wrong?
万一出事了 怎么办
It...
这
happened suddenly.
事发有点突然
What's so sudden?
有什么突然的呀
You
这突然
could still tell me.
你也可以告诉我呀
There's always a process.
它总有个过程吧
If something happens,
这一发生
just call me,
你马上给我打电话
and I'll be there right away.
我马上就冲过去了
Who's bullying you?
谁欺负你啊
I can help you.
我帮你打她
I have nothing to do at home.
你说我在家也没事
Why didn't you call me
你 你这有事了
when you needed help?
你还不叫我
You're making me anxious.
你要着急死我呀
I couldn't
那我也不能
ask you to handle this.
叫你帮我干这事啊
Since you're at home doing nothing,
你在家没事干
maybe you should find a job.
要不要出来找份工作啊
It could
这样的话
help distract
也可以分散一下
your attention.
自己的注意力
When I was at home,
我当时在家的时候
I used to overthink.
也会胡思乱想
After I started working,
出来工作以后
I felt more fulfilled.
反而觉得生活 很充实
I think Wanzhen
我觉得你婉真姐这话
has a point.
说得挺有道理的
Maybe you can
你要不要
give it a try.
试试
Hi.
来啦
Where are the kids?
孩子们呢
Well,
那个
come in first.
你先进来吧
I'm here to pick up the kids.
我来接孩子的
They're
那个
with their Grandpa.
孩子们在爷爷那儿呢
I'll go get them.
那我去接她们
Wait.
别别别 那个
They haven't seen Grandpa
那孩子好长时间
for a while.
没见着爷爷了
Let them
让爷爷
spend more time with him.
跟俩孩子多玩会儿
Look, I...
这 我呢 我 我在
I found a video online
网上我找这个视频
and made two dishes
我做了两道菜
specifically for you.
专门为你做的
How about
那个
we sit down,
咱们要不 坐下来
eat
吃点东西
and chat?
聊聊
It's fine.
还行
It's
这
not dark cuisine.
它不是什么黑暗料理
It's edible.
能吃
I made them with my heart.
我的一份心意
Fine.
行
Really?
真的
Mr Zhou said
听周总说
you have
你们蓝海
a new acquisition plan.
有个新的并购方案
Why didn't you tell me?
为什么不告诉我
No.
不是
That day,
那个
with the kid's birthday
那天吧 孩子过生日
and
加上呢
the Xinmiao issue,
新苗出了那个事
I suddenly
我就突然间
had this idea.
有这么个想法
I told Mr Zhou
我就跟周总说了
to ask his opinion
我也想探探他的口风
and whether he supports it.
看他支持不支持
I didn't expect
这没想到
he'd be so supportive.
他还挺支持的
So, you think I'm insignificant
看来我这个项目负责人
as the project lead?
在你眼里什么都不是啊
No.
不是
No,
没有
not at all.
绝对没有这个意思
I just feel
我是因为
the plan isn't fully developed yet.
那个方案它还不够系统
I'll present it to you
我 我把它彻底写出来
once it's complete.
我一定向你汇报
Alright.
行
Let's clear this up
那今天把这个事
today.
说明白
Talk it through.
聊个透
Today's atmosphere...
不是这 今天这个气氛
Good-looking.
好看
Try it.
你 你尝尝
Maybe it needs
这 是不是应该
a bit more
再加点那个
vinegar?
什么醋
Mr Yu,
于总啊
now you have time to learn to cook?
你现在有时间学做饭了
Yes, I've realized how hard
是 我是现在我才知道
it's been for you all these years.
你这些年你有多不容易
I even cut my finger earlier.
我刚才还切下手指头
I can't imagine how many times
都不知道这些年你
you've cut yourself.
切过多少次手指头了
Is it good?
那个 还 还能吃吧
No.
真不好吃
It's okay. It's just an appetizer.
没事 这是前菜啊
Finally, you're here.
终于来了你
Cheers.
来
Go ahead.
说吧
What a lovely day it is.
今天天气真好啊
Our home feels so cozy.
你看咱们家多舒服啊
Talk about the plan.
说方案
Well, Wanzhen,
是这样啊 婉真
we've been
这段时间呢
together again recently,
这咱们俩又在一起了
for working,
当然是工作
working,
咱们是工作啊
and it reminds me
让我想起了
of the old days.
很多年前的事
It reminds me of
上大学时候的
you from college.
那个你又出现了
The one I admired, liked,
让我喜欢 让我欣赏
and pursued.
让我追求的那个你
Even though you were thin,
虽然说你瘦瘦的
you were so capable
但是你特别地干练啊
and strong.
特别地坚强
Over the years after we got married,
真的 这些年结婚
I've been wrong.
都是我的错
I've been selfish.
我太自私了
I took it for granted
我太心安理得地
and trapped you in this home,
我就把你困在这个家里
making you a housewife.
让你做家庭主妇了
I treated you
我完全把你
as an accessory to the family
当成了这个家和我的
and me.
附属品
I sincerely apologize.
我非常郑重地向你道歉
I'm sorry.
对不起
You don't need
其实你不用
to apologize to me.
跟我说对不起
Being a full-time wife
做全职太太
was my choice.
是我自己的选择
After having kids,
有了孩子之后
I just wanted to give them
我只想给她们一个
a stable home.
稳定的家
But
但是
I wasn't satisfied.
我不甘心
No, it's all my fault.
不 是 都是我的错
Well,
这个
I was wrong.
我 我错了
Hi, Windy.
温蒂
Mr Yu.
于总
Mr Zhou.
周总
Why is he here?
他怎么来了
I invited him
我请他来的
to discuss
一起聊一下
the Blue Ocean acquisition.
蓝海并购的事情
Here, take this.
这 你拿着这个
Mr Zhou.
周总
I could smell the food from far away.
老远就闻到香味了
I came
真是来得早
at the right time.
不如来得巧啊
I haven't eaten yet, so I'll
我正好没吃饭 我就
help myself.
不客气了
Hey,
那个什么
get a chair and tableware.
拿个椅子 拿套餐具啊
Thanks.
谢谢啊
It's an honor
周总能到我家来
to have you visit my home.
真是让我这儿蓬荜生辉
No,
没有
I'm here mainly because of Wendy.
我来主要因为有温蒂
We had an appointment
我本来约的温蒂
with an investment banker,
去见一个投行的朋友
and since she's here,
她说在这儿
I came over.
那我就过来吧
That's fine.
不过没关系
We can eat first
我们可以先吃
and
晚一点咱们
meet the friend later.
再去见那个朋友
Okay.
好
You're back.
回来啦
Why so many things?
怎么买这么多东西啊
Mr Zhang bought these for you.
你们张总给你的补品
Mr Zhang's here?
张总来啦
Where's him?
人呢
I didn't let him come up.
我没让他上来
What did he buy?
买的什么呀
Sea cucumber.
海参啊
Does your hand hurt?
手还疼不疼
Hand?
手
No.
手不疼啊
You pulled her hair?
你薅人头发了
How could you hit her?
你怎么可以打人呢
I...
我 知知知
I know.
知道 知道
I was so angry and
我当时就是太生气了
couldn't control myself.
就 就没控 控制住
Wendy asked me about
温蒂可向我兴师问罪了
the Blue Ocean acquisition.
关于蓝海并购的意向
Why wasn't she informed
她作为直接负责人
since she's
为什么没有
the person in charge?
第一时间知道
Yu, I'm not taking the blame for this.
于总 这锅我可不背啊
You discussed it
那天是你
with me while you were
带着孩子的时候
with the kids,
跟我商量
and I thought it was a good idea.
我觉得挺好
But you should have notified
但你应该第一时间
the direct supervisor right away.
通知直属负责人吧
Yes.
是是是
Well,
那个
sorry, Wendy.
对不起啊 温蒂总
During that time,
我那段时间
I was dealing with the kids,
我这带孩子带的吧
and my mind was a mess.
我这脑袋都快炸了
Now I've realized
我这才知道
you've really had
温蒂总这些年
a tough time with the kids.
带孩子是真不容易
Sorry, Wendy.
对不起啊 温蒂总
You don't need to apologize.
你不用道歉了
Uh-oh, Mr Yu,
完了 于总
you've really offended Wendy.
彻底把温蒂得罪了
Let me tell you,
我告诉你啊
she's
她这个人
ruthless
睚眦必报
and vengeful.
心狠手辣
I'm not in charge of
这个项目
the project.
我说了都不算
If Wendy sabotages you
万一将来温蒂
in the future,
给你使绊子
I'm not responsible.
我可不负责任啊
Mr Zhou, you taught me this.
周总 这都是你教的啊
I'm much kinder than you.
我比你仁慈多了 好吗
Have you forgotten
你忘了你
your nickname in the industry?
在行业里的绰号了
What nickname?
什么绰号
Zhou the Benevolent, huh?
周大善人 是吧
Every project you handle,
你过手的项目
you peel off a layer of skin.
哪有不扒层皮的呀
You are the Skin Peeler.
周扒皮 周扒皮
Not everyone can be that.
不是谁都能当的
Skin Peeler?
周扒皮都出来了
Alright, alright, you win.
行行行 我说不过你啊
You win.
我说不过你
Come on.
来 来
Cheers.
开心
Here.
来
Cheers, Wendy.
来 温蒂
Wendy.
温蒂总
Introduce this chef to me.
这个厨师你介绍给我
I'll invite him if I'm having
下次我家里有聚会
a party next time.
我也请他来
Okay.
好的 好的
I'll pass his WeChat
我把他微信啊
to your secretary.
推给您秘书
Okay.
好的
Mr Zhou,
周总
thank you.
那个 谢谢您啊
Thank me for what?
谢 谢我什么
Last time,
那个 上次
when you and Wanzhen
您跟婉真
were on a business trip
你们一块儿出差
and it was her birthday,
正好赶上过生日
you helped me
然后你还帮着我
give her a surprise.
给了她一个惊喜
We joined you
我们不是带着孩子
with the kids.
一块儿跟你们汇合吗
It's nothing.
你想多了
Just
小事
a small favor.
举手之劳
Wanzhen missed the kids
婉真想孩子
and I needed to see you
我找你又有事
so I called you.
所以把你叫来了
Just like that.
想多了
I thought
我还以为您
you were helping us.
是为了帮我们呢
Helping you?
帮你们什么
I want to reconcile with Wanzhen.
我呢 想跟婉真复婚
I can see that.
看出来了
But it
但这事
depends on her thought.
你知道婉真想不想啊
I hope
所以我也希望
she thinks so.
她能这么想
I'm still working on it.
反正我正在努力
Mr Yu, some things
于总 有些事情
can't be achieved just by working.
它不是努力就能做成的
It
这事呢
depends on Wanzhen's attitude.
还得看婉真的态度
Yes.
是是是
After all, we have
我们毕竟呢
two daughters.
有两个女儿
And I will also
而且以后呢 我也会
respect
尊重她在
her work decisions
工作这方面的想法
and support her
我会支持她
in doing a good job.
帮您把工作做好
It seems you really
看来你真的
want to reconcile with her.
很想跟她复婚
In that case,
那以后
I won't help you
我就不会像上次
again.
那样帮你了
I'll even advise Wanzhen
我还会劝婉真
not to reconcile with you.
不要跟你复婚